<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contributions on Kean J. Hsu, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contributions on Kean J. Hsu, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic cognitive processes</title>
      <link>/contributions/basic-cognitive-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributions/basic-cognitive-processes/</guid>
      <description>Basic cognitive processes (e.g., attention and executive functioning) regulate what information from the environment enters conscious processing and how well that information can be processed and utilized or discarded. When these processes go awry, particularly in the context of negatively-valenced information or stimuli, they may lead to negative mood states and factors associated with depression risk and depression severity. We were the first group to show that while identical twins discordant for depression show no differences in neuropsychological functioning, they exhibit attentional impairment relative to identical twins with no family history of depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repetitive Negative Thinking</title>
      <link>/contributions/rnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributions/rnt/</guid>
      <description>Repetitive negative thinking (e.g., rumination; RNT) is a transdiagnostic process of increasing interest in theoretical models of psychopathology and in empirical study. My research into RNT in complex psychiatric samples has been broadly based, including the study of measure psychometrics, potential mechanisms underlying RNT, and how RNT often mediates treatment outcomes. For example, although the Ruminative Responses Scale (RRS) has been suggested as a two-factor measure of rumination in student samples, factor analyses of the RRS in psychiatric samples have suggested other factor solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The measurement of psychopathology and associated processes</title>
      <link>/contributions/psychometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributions/psychometrics/</guid>
      <description>Our ability to advance our understanding of psychopathology is inherently limited by the tools and frameworks we adopt. I have two lines of work based on this premise.
1) Instruments assessing clinical constructs have often been developed and validated in non-clinical settings (e.g., with university subject pools). Limited work has been conducted examining the validity and reliability of these instruments in more transdiagnostic clinical samples despite their prevalence in clinical research spanning a variety of psychiatric disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment development and research</title>
      <link>/contributions/treatment-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributions/treatment-research/</guid>
      <description>While clinical science has yielded a number of psychotherapeutic interventions that benefit individuals with a broad range of psychopathology, not everyone benefits from these treatments and it is still unclear how these treatments work. Consequently, there is a significant need for research into the predictors and mediators of treatment response, particularly beyond traditional randomized clinical trial settings. We have examined factors involved in treatment response for a complex psychiatric sample presenting for treatment in a partial hospital setting, finding support for the relevance of therapeutic skill change, rumination, and treatment expectancy in prediction of therapeutic response.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>