<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basic cognitive processes on Kean J. Hsu, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/tags/basic-cognitive-processes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Basic cognitive processes on Kean J. Hsu, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/basic-cognitive-processes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic cognitive processes</title>
      <link>/contributions/basic-cognitive-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributions/basic-cognitive-processes/</guid>
      <description>Basic cognitive processes (e.g., attention and executive functioning) regulate what information from the environment enters conscious processing and how well that information can be processed and utilized or discarded. When these processes go awry, particularly in the context of negatively-valenced information or stimuli, they may lead to negative mood states and factors associated with depression risk and depression severity. We were the first group to show that while identical twins discordant for depression show no differences in neuropsychological functioning, they exhibit attentional impairment relative to identical twins with no family history of depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COmputerized Modification Program for Attention - REtraining the Mind Trial (COMPARE Mind Trial)</title>
      <link>/project/r33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r33/</guid>
      <description>Further details coming soon. 
Project Abstract (from NIH RePORTER): The overall goal of this project is to continue development of an attention bias modification (ABM) intervention that targets and reduces negative attention bias among adults with elevated symptoms of depression. Our prior work indicates that attention bias for negative information is associated with the maintenance of depression and that neural circuitry within frontal-parietal brain networks supports biased attention for negative information, thus allowing us to develop specific and targeted interventions that directly alter the neurobiology of negative attention bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain, Motivation and Personality Development Study (BrainMAPD)</title>
      <link>/project/brainmapd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/brainmapd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions of genome-wide variability to cognitive vulnerability to depression</title>
      <link>/project/r56/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r56/</guid>
      <description>Further details coming soon. 
Project Abstract (from NIH RePORTER): Depression is a leading cause of disability worldwide among adults. Cognitive models of depression, which have received strong empirical support, posit that individuals&amp;rsquo; characteristic ways of attending to, interpreting, and remembering stimuli in their environment may contribute to the development and maintenance of the disorder. To understand the etiology of these biases, many genetic association studies have been completed. However, findings so far (including those from our own work) have been somewhat limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transdiagnostic cognitive inflexibility</title>
      <link>/project/cog-inflex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cog-inflex/</guid>
      <description>Further details coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>